supermommyclub.com 2019-06-15

# Privacy Policy

## How we use your personal information

Your information will be held by Just Bright Ideas.

This privacy notice is to let you know how we promise to look after your personal information. This includes what you tell us about yourself, what we learn by having you as a reader, and the choices you give us about what marketing you want us to send you.

This notice also tells you about your privacy rights and how the law protects you.

Last updated: May 4, 2018.

### Our Privacy Promise

We promise:

  * To keep your data safe and private.
  * Not to sell your data.
  * To give you ways to manage and review your marketing choices at any time.

## How the law protects you

This section sets out the legal reasons we rely on, for each of the ways we may use your personal information.

As well as our Privacy Promise, your privacy is protected by law. This section explains how that works.

Data Protection law says that we are allowed to use personal information only if we have a proper reason to do so. This includes sharing it with third parties. The law says we must have one or more of these reasons:

  * To fulfil a contract we have with you, or
  * When it is our legal duty, or
  * When it is in our legitimate interest, or
  * When you consent to it.

When we have a business reason of our own to use your information, this is called a ‘legitimate interest’. We will tell you what that is, if we are going to rely on it as the reason for using your data. Even then, it must not unfairly go against your interests.

## About the data we collect and store

This section is about the personally identifiable information (PII) and anonymous information that we may collect when you visit our website.

### Personally Identifiable Data

Here is a list of all the ways that we may use your personal information, and which of the legal reasons we rely on to do so. This is also where we tell you what our legitimate interests are.

 **Website Security**

We collect the the IP address of your device to manage security for legitimate interests.

When you visit our website your IP address is logged by our server and our Content Delivery Network in order to protect it from risks such as a hacking attempt. This data cannot be accessed by third parties and is deleted after 24 hours.

The data is stored on our servers which are provided by Digital Ocean in conjunction with Serverpilot. And by our Content Delivery Network which is provided by Cloudflare. None of these companies has access to the data.

 **Email marketing**

If you voluntarily opt in to one of our marketing newsletters by giving us consent to use your email address we store your IP address and country (legitimate interests) in order to prove that you consented (explicit consent) to us storing your email address and using it for marketing purposes.

Your data is retained while you are subscribed to our newsletter and after you have unsubscribed as it is used for data analysis purposes.

It is stored in the database of our email provider Mailerlite. They do not have access to your data.

### Anonymous Data

From time to time, we may use anonymous data, which does not identify you alone, or when combined with data from other parties. This type of anonymous data may be provided to other parties for marketing, advertising, or other uses.

Here is a list of all the ways that we may use anonymous data.

 **Website Analytics**

We automatically collect certain information about you and the device with which you access our website.

We collect this data in order to understand website usage and user experience and to help us develop content to enhance your user experience. The data is viewed as a population and it is not possible to isolate your information or your activity from the whole.

For example, when you use the website, we will log your operating system type, browser type, referring website, pages you viewed, and the dates/times when you accessed the website. We may also collect information about actions you take when using the website, such as links clicked.

This anonymous data is stored in the databases of Google Analytics and Statcounter who provide our website analytics.

 **Affiliate Marketing**

We take part in affiliate marketing which is done by embedding tracking links into the website. If you click on a link for an affiliate partnership, a cookie will be placed on your browser to track any sales for purposes of commissions.

We currently work with Amazon Associates, Awin, Shareasale, Perfect Keto and Shopstyle Collective. This list may be amended from time to time at our sole discretion.

The data is stored in the database of the Affiliate Partnership.

 **Newsletter**

You may decide to subscribe to our newsletter, which may be used for advertising purposes.

All newsletters sent may contain tracking pixels. The pixel is embedded in emails and allows an analysis of the success of online marketing campaigns. Because of these tracking pixels, we may see if and when you open an email and which links within the email you click.

This information allows us to adapt the content of future newsletters to the interests of our readers.

This behavior information will not be passed on to third parties.

The data is stored in the database of Google Analytics and Mailerlite who provide our web analytics and email service respectively.

 **Advertising**

We use third-party advertising companies to serve content and advertisements when you visit the website.

They may use cookies to ensure that visitors are not repeatedly shown the same banner ads or to customise the content of those adverts based on visitors’ browser type or other information that the visitor sends.

The information collected is used by the advertisers to ensure you are shown appropriate advertising and is stored in their databases.

### Sensitive Personal Information

At no time should you submit sensitive personal information to the website.

This includes information about racial or ethnic origin, sexual orientation, religious beliefs, trade union membership, health data, and criminal records. 

If you elect to submit such information to us, it will be subject to this Privacy Policy.

### Cookies

This section contains a link to our Cookie Policy

Cookies are small computer files that get sent down to your PC, tablet or mobile phone by websites when you visit them. They stay on your device and get sent back to the website they came from, when you go there again.

Cookies store information about your visits to that website, such as your choices and other details. Some of this data does not contain personal details about you or your business, but it is still protected by this Privacy notice.

To find out more about how we use cookies, please see our [Cookie Policy](https://justbrightideas.com/cookie-policy/).

## Your rights

What if you want us to stop using your personal information? This section explains about your right to object and other data privacy rights you have – as well as how to contact us about them.

 **Opt-out** – You may opt-out of future email communications by following the unsubscribe links in our emails. You may also notify us at webmaster@justbrightideas.com to be removed from our mailing list.

 **Access** – You may access the personal information we have about you by submitting a request to webmaster@justbrightideas.com.

 **Amend** – You may contact us athello@justbrightideas.com to amend or update your personal information.

 **Forget** – In certain situations, you may request that we erase or forget your personal data. To do so, please submit a request to webmaster@justbrightideas.com.

Please note that we may need to retain certain information for record keeping purposes or to complete transactions, or when required by law.

## Children’s information

We do not knowingly collect any personally identifiable information from children under the age of 16.

If a parent or guardian believes that the website has personally identifiable information of a child under the age of 16 in its database, please contact us immediately at webmaster@justbrightideas.com and we will use our best efforts to promptly remove such information from our records.

## Contact information

Please contact us at webmaster@justbrightideas.com for questions related to this Privacy Policy.
